{
    "id": "a90295bb1a2d48938dd1235bf1c05083",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "We went out ………………….. the rain.",
            "description": "In spite of is the correct expression. It is a preposition. Because is a conjunction. ",
            "answers": [
                "in spite of",
                "despite of",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "There is a school ..................... my house.",
            "description": "You can't possibly have a school in front of your house. To express the idea 'on the other side of the road', we use opposite. ",
            "answers": [
                "in front of",
                "opposite"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If it ..................... for his wife’s money, he would never be a film producer.",
            "description": "In the second conditional both wasn't and weren't are possible with singular subjects. ",
            "answers": [
                "wasn't",
                "weren't",
                "isn't",
                "Either wasn't or weren't"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "……………….. I realized what you intended, I wouldn’t have permitted this.",
            "description": "The correct expression is 'If I had realized what you intended,...'",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "should",
                "if"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Had we not cancelled our tickets, we .....................…… in the accident.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use would have + past participle form of the verb to express hypothetical ideas.",
            "answers": [
                "would be killed",
                "would have been killed",
                "will be killed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "There is little ...................... good evidence for flying saucers.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "if",
                "if any",
                "any"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I would have been in bad trouble, if you .....................…… me.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use would have + past participle in the main clause and past perfect tense in the if-clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "didn't help",
                "hadn't helped",
                "don't help"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You ......................... better turn that music down before your dad gets angry.",
            "description": "The correct expression is 'had better'.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "could"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Take your coat and pass me ......................",
            "description": "My is a possessive adjective and mine is a possessive pronoun. My is used before a noun. Mine is used alone. ",
            "answers": [
                "my",
                "mine"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "This house ................................. in",
            "description": "We need a passive form here because the subject is not the doer of the action. ",
            "answers": [
                "built",
                "was built"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}